hey everybody welcome to the podcast
it's me your host helga pataki i'm glad
you're here this week we've got devon
mullins on the podcast he is a cannabis
industry consultant he spent a few years
as a worker in the cannabis industry as
a bud tender working in various
situations working in the recreational
world working in the medicinal world now
he's over in missouri
managing and opening up new stores in
the medicinal cannabis industry he's
knowledgeable we're really trying to
bring a beginner's mindset to this
episode and try to just kind of describe
where we're at in the cannabis world um
and kind of what the experience is like
for a newcomer so if you are new to
marijuana new to weed new to cannabis
new to pot
or you just don't know too much about
what's going on in the world of it we
kind of covered that sort of area now
and some basics so i hope you enjoyed
the episode we did have a couple uh
cutouts we had a couple times where we
lost connection so i did my best to try
to stitch the episode back in it's not
the uh not the typical audio quality you
are used to uh it's certainly not
insufferable by any means um be totally
fine you probably wouldn't notice it
much if i didn't know if i didn't
mention it but
nonetheless it's worth it to me to say
something about it so
i hope you enjoyed the episode if you
did uh consider
subscribing liking commenting wherever
you do listen to it if you could just
hit that one button the little five star
that comment that follow anything just
real quick i don't want to take too much
of your time but it is greatly
appreciated appreciated any interaction
you have with the episodes it helps the
algorithms kind of give them out to more
people and let's more people hear the
podcast if you are just listening to the
episode uh know that the last uh
the episodes are actually available on
youtube for visual as well um so if you
want to watch the episodes if you want
to watch se amaron feel free it's on
youtube jacob from the internet or just
search the junkyard love podcast they'll
pop up i also post clips and trailers on
my instagram jacob from the internet so
check those out um
yeah hope you enjoyed the episode we'll
see you next time peace
what is it so is it a lot of people with
with like headaches back problems oh
yeah yes um
it's everything it's from you know you
believe some neuropathic diseases to you
know
fibromyalgia to headaches and migraines
to um
i mean anxiety depression it's in an
endless list of things that
it benefits people in
reality is
[Music]
well i work with it all day man uh we
get a lot of these uh patient caregivers
that don't smoke but they know
everything about this weed
yeah
it's funny some of them are afraid to
come in the store but you know it's
medical out here so it's all weird
you're on a list
yeah oh yeah yeah yeah i mean dude it's
it the stigma is obviously unfolding and
melting away in certain places but it's
going to take a while for us to like
challenge those
those unconscious beliefs of what we
think about the whole thing as a society
it's
it's crazy out here you know it's it's
different the
it's a bunch of farmers like old school
farmer dudes out here and now they're
like yo this pharmaceutical is too
expensive and i'm not paying those ways
so they come back to weed and they're
like they try it out and they love it
it's awesome dude
hell yeah dude i mean i'm smoking weed
out on a farm just chilling out by
yourself mowing the lawn that's a bad
that's a good day right there man right
yeah yeah um all right bro i'm i'm ready
if you have any questions for me or
anything that you want from me nope um
just let me know if
let me know if i do too much if i i'm
gonna try and filter myself out i mean i
don't think i'll cuss too much i'm
pretty good about it but you're getting
aware about the conversation yeah it's
not the disney channel you're good buddy
you feel free to just be yourself don't
don't even worry don't don't worry about
tiptoeing around you know it's it's not
like i've got like this playing at
schools or anything you're good man just
be yourself cool welcome folks
to the junkyard love podcast today i'm
here with my friend
devin
what's up man
how you doing brother i'm swell man i'm
swell i'm super pumped uh i'm pumped to
have you on we've talked about this a
couple times before
and i feel like every day you just get
more knowledge into your brain about
this whole field so it's it's great to
finally get you on here and just pick
your brain about this whole thing yeah
man i mean it's a it it and every day
still to this day it's like a new day of
new knowledge that comes in
whether it be from patients or you know
other growers or you know just just
other users and
it's pretty awesome and it's it's
growing more and more um it's so cool
that it's becoming more legal because
that that means more research and more
studies for us to know this and
get our knowledge
yeah exactly i mean even the anecdotal
stuff that you get just walking it like
people walking in the door explaining
maybe like their desires or their you
know psychosomatic symptoms or their
ailments like whatever's whatever they
got going on you get to like learn oh
yeah i had this guy two weeks ago that
came in and he also had headaches and
this strain helped him you know whatever
it is you're kind of connecting the dots
of of the marijuana behind it the
growers how they grow it what it is
about that certain strain that um and
then eventually you know we'll be able
to really connect these to like our
psychology as humans like what strain
affects this way and why and that's
gonna be really cool dude
so much stuff man i mean literally you
just put it all like that is exactly it
and that's why this is a it's an
industry i don't know if i'll ever leave
now you know i'm so in love with it um
and passionate about it and truly enjoy
it it's hard not to like it's hard not
to have a good day
i love that i love you yeah i mean
that's contagious too honestly like when
you walk into a store and and the people
working there uh are just like they're
happy you could tell that they're
enjoying their job they're just kind of
you know bs with people who are
like-minded about things that they enjoy
they love learning about the product
like you can feel it it's a comforting
space to walk into a lot of these stores
it's it's very rewarding um and like you
know becky said i feel like it's a
patient's zero you know i'm right there
with the people that are telling me
these things that this is helping with
you know and uh this is this is as close
as it gets to
uh science without science you know i'm
not doing anything
you know no chemical
anything or you know no nothing like
crazy scientific about it i'm just
telling these people that these terpenes
and these different compounds and these
flowers will help you with certain
things from experience of other patients
you know right yeah i mean
dips into psychology more than more than
just like science in a lab rather
exactly exactly yeah so okay well so
dude give me the
give me the lowdown you can give me the
long form too i like we we're here we
got some time what is your like
background in this area when did you
start uh what what have you done like
what led you to where you're at
yeah
um a quick little uh thing
i i mean weed has been a part of my life
since i can remember uh the first day
i really truly like remembering uh it
started in when i was 12 years old
i was down in berkeley california with
my grandmother and we're driving down
some you know basic street in california
and there's this big building blacked
out black walls black mirror or black uh
bags looking things in the windows and
she said that's where i get my medicine
and uh from that day on i was like
what's that grandma that's not the
typical pharmacy you see you know
that's not the medicine i usually see
you get it from
um and then it was always been a
question and a curiosity but nothing
that ever was like i needed to know um i
actually didn't smoke weed until i was
like 17 years old oh really um and uh i
don't know if you ever heard of the
comedian jim brewer
i have yeah yeah okay uh i like to think
i was a lot like him man um i gave off
i had this face you know this this
common face and my eyes were always kind
of low i was a lazy sleepy dude so it
looked like i was baked all the time in
high school and i wasn't even smoking
weed i was just a [__] you know chill
back laid down dude that just yeah i
guess was i slept a lot i don't know
um but uh back to that i uh i started
smoking in high school after you know
what people say is a common breakup your
big breakup i was like i'm gonna smoke
weed you know um not even realizing the
uh the amount it would or the impact
you'd have in my life
from then on um
in a good way in a very good way you
know um
i actually uh i smoked weed you know had
a good time
before i knew it um i was taking
migraine medicine in middle school and
up to high school
and i uh
in high school typical you know smoker
is what you would say
just to get fun and have a good time i
didn't realize that i'd stopped taking
my migraine meds and just
subliminally one day stopped i was
smoking weed wasn't getting headaches
and this was you know at 17 18.
um and i stopped taking that medicine um
kept on smoking weed you know i went to
college got kicked out of college for
smoke and weed
um
it was a technical school they test i
failed whatever
um
i ended up moving to colorado to get
away from weed and i found the best weed
in my life
um came back from there and was actually
becoming i was a laborer did landscaping
and then i became a cook
and then my server one day was like hey
um i'm gonna go work in the weed
industry i'm gonna be a bud tender and i
was like what that's crazy i'm coming
with you little did i know i'd actually
be with her three weeks later and we
both started working and that was the
start of my career in the cannabis
industry
that was the start of me learning about
canvas more than just how high i get or
how high it gets you or the different
ways of smoking
um that's when uh that was like 2000 uh
2013 14 2014. so and cannabis has just
become illegal in washington and it's
becoming legal in california colorado
shortly
and it was like man i could i could do
something with this you know i could go
somewhere with this and make something
out of it
and uh i worked my way up the ladder
with the cannabis company
[Music]
i went from
packaging edibles to
controlling the inventory
uh to inside sales and then ending up
becoming a uh sales and ops or a uh a
sales
representative for the company and uh
through all these years um i gained this
knowledge of what cannabis does for you
um beyond you know the typical
psychoactive high there's
thc and then there's cbd
you know and there's all these other
things but um so i've been in this
cannabis industry
eight years now um
it's been
amazing and good and still learning
every day all this new stuff
um but that's that's kind of the
background of cannabis and where i came
from and why i'm still in it
yeah so what's your so you're you're out
in missouri and you're doing um you're
managing medicinals
yeah yeah so uh i guess you know
uh that's that's the i guess i i need to
go a little bit detail too i started in
washington in the washington cannabis
industry um i worked as a at a producer
processor and then i worked as a bud
tender as well
and um you know i was looking for a
change of pace and something else and i
had uh
i'd reached out to somebody out in
missouri that was in cannabis out here
and
they're like hey man come out um check
us out give us a resume and see if this
is something you'd like and
um we're we're more about
just
we're more than just selling cannabis
we're trying to be more on the education
and the patients first side
we want to offer
knowledge and education these cut these
patients and help them with these
certain illness and illnesses and
ailments and
they thought that i would do great with
helping them with that my experience in
knowledge and cannabis and
yeah it's it i've been out here since
january and i started in uh march
and it's been good man it's been really
good um
the the rewards of helping people these
certain things
uh is beyond anything you can imagine so
do you get do you get people who don't
really
do you get people who don't really know
uh like you know like some old lady or
something that walks in there is like i
have no idea about weed but my grandkids
told me to try it or whatever like like
what do you get like people who are
really knowledgeable out there or is it
just i have no idea about this but i
heard it will help or
everybody everybody you want to believe
you know uh me coming out to midwest uh
when i first met out here i had these
dealers selling me these this weed this
is the most expensive weed i've bought
in my life
um you know and
uh
i uh i get this i get the same people
that were buying weed and then i get
these people that are like i didn't know
they still sold weed on the streets and
i get these people being like i didn't
even know you guys are illegal yet um
yeah you get all aspects especially
um you know it's funny that you brought
up the uh the pre the patient that has a
grandkid that's like hey uh grandpa you
should try this hey grandma you should
try this and they try one gummy and that
said that was the best day of their life
you know
they never felt so much pain relief uh
they never felt like they felt like a
kid again is a lot of things you get um
and it's you know
it's
it's blissful you know the the the
reward the smile you see in their face
are like man i'm so glad this is
happening and missouri just became legal
like medically i think
october 2020. so these people are like
this is a newfound
medicine you know it's exactly
as it is it's medicine you know um
what's the uh so what is the difference
between so we have states that are
recreationally legal where you can just
go like as long as you're over the age
of 21 you can go and purchase it and
then we have states um in certain areas
that are medicinal only could you kind
of explain the divide the difference
here yeah yeah so um recreational is
typically you know it mainly it's it's
just the
the state's way of
legalizing marijuana um recreational is
for the every per anybody that's 21 and
up they can use it
there's no
unfortunately it's it's up to either the
store um the people working in the
industry and the patient on finding
knowledge most of the time
um because you know recreational states
are typically aimed towards sales like
you know liquor and stuff and etc
so you will find companies that go
beyond that point to help you guide your
way through this process especially in
recreational
but most of the time it's just uh it's
also just you know i'd rather have i'd
rather have a joint than a beer at the
end of the night if that makes sense and
that's really nice for people
alcohol is great it's a good time sure
but it it leads to a lot of problems you
know and i feel like marijuana can
it can be done in so many ways and so
non-lethal and so fun you know the
difference between drinking a beer
before bed and smoking a joint before
bed is just real real variant yes so
when it comes to recreational states
it's it's easier access um easier for
everybody it's usually cheaper which is
awesome um and it's just like uh
it i just think i i love recreational i
love the fact that it's so easy and
accessible to everybody and there's no
limit you know
um it's it the the positive impact on
you know criminal activity and such too
even people getting away from other
drugs
but uh the recreational usually comes
way after the medical side and so when
you see a state go medical you can you
can pretty much predict two to three
years from there it's going to go wreck
um and that's kind of what's happened
the last you know well besides
california washington their medical
forever before we got this you know
recreational side
um so when it comes to medical um it's a
lot harder to access you have to find a
doctor you have to get a referral
and then you have to be approved by
whatever state agency is you know
controlling that medical marijuana
and
here in missouri in one example they
they don't do anything
easy for the medical marijuana patient
it's all online
they don't send you anything by mail
it's all email
and i get 95 96 you know
80 and above is a common patient 80
years old and above is a competition in
the medical industry
um because you know they're the ones
that really need it as much as everybody
needs it that qualifies for it and every
any person
in the world can use it and benefit from
it but uh
the medical side is definitely a lot
harder um it's a lot more regulated
and uh it's difficult but it's also it's
nice it's nice for the people that
need it and uh it's kind of like a
a path you know it's a path to start
so what what is their process like they
go in
what what are the typical the typical
ailments that you find people i mean i
don't know how like sharing or forward
people are about why they're coming in
to get it from you they don't they don't
exactly have to tell you you know they
just have the card and they can buy it
but just from what you hear through
friendly conversation
what is it so is it a lot of people with
with like headaches back problems oh
yeah yes
it's everything it's from you know you
believe from neuropathic diseases to you
know
fibromyalgia to headaches and migraines
to
i mean anxiety depression it's in an
endless list of things that
it benefits people in um
um
personally um it helps you with anxiety
you know there's there's cool things
about this this weed and marijuana and
cannabis that really um that i wish more
people would knew and i i i hope
becomes more knowledgeable amongst like
the the major media i guess you could
say and you're seeing it too and you are
seeing it too and this is my scatter
brain sorry jake and sorry the listeners
with my scatter brain goes back and
forth
um
yes but uh no um
uh when it comes to those patients and
those certain illnesses you know i had
we're not supposed to talk you know
beyond hipaa law so i have to refer to
them as patients obviously
um i i get chronic migraines and i
haven't since i smoked marijuana um when
i don't smoke say i have to go a week
without it because i'm going to a state
or somewhere where it's not allowed
i try to say that i don't do it but i
always find a way to bring it with me
it's my medicine but i've gone you know
a weeks or so without doing it you know
sometimes you can't smoke because of you
know you just need to chill back and
relax and ease your mind um whatever you
know but uh
it's
it's it's a good it's a good thing um
in other other ways of like uh
decreasing appetite
uh getting your energy going getting you
up and going for the day you know it
doesn't always have to be a sedating or
a relaxing lethargic get high relax and
mellow out and eat food it can be the
complete opposite
and that's the knowledge i want people
to know you know yeah yeah dude yeah
because that's i definitely want to dip
our toes into this water pretty pretty
heavily because so you know my
experience with marijuana when i was
living back in washington i was smoking
a lot smoking fairly often and it wasn't
at all a you know because we have this
typical stigma i like i think we're a
few years past the stigma but maybe it's
around for some people of this oh you're
just gonna get high and watch a movie
and you're gonna eat chips on your couch
and just kind of whatever and like cool
like if that's what you do like hell
yeah man do it but uh but like yeah so
me it would it would help with anxiety
it would help me get present um it
helped me like i would i would smoke and
i would do yoga i would smoke and i
would go run 10 miles like i like when
it comes to fitness athleticism
smoking a little bit of weed before is
so great it gets you both in your mind
and out of your mind you know like or if
you're um if you're gonna like read a
book or something on audible you're
gonna go for a walk there's there's all
these different applications you can be
like oh
here's these things that i normally love
to do or use these things i normally
love to do with other people let me try
to do them solo and let's add a little
smoking to it i'm a person who likes um
solo smoking more than i i of course
enjoy you know a good social setting um
in the right set and setting the right
environment the right people around me
um where i you know i i feel like just
just comfortable don't have to put on
any mask or anything like that just
smoking in those those myers but mainly
solo and i had a lot of good benefits
from it helped me a lot with my
depression helped me a lot with my
anxiety um
and being able to i feel like in
washington in states that are legal it's
you're so spoiled because
there's just so many different strains
and there's just so many different
applications for those strains and you
walk into the store and you're like hey
man i want to uh i'm gonna go skydiving
later do you have a strain for that he's
like i got you and you're like after
that i'm gonna go eat a pizza and sit in
my backyard and he's like oh i gotta
stay free like you tell me that's
spot-on yeah right right okay so so
explain that like
that whole side of being able to
recommend to people like based off of
they come in they they have a certain
desire they have a certain emotion
you're actually able to kind of fill it
like oh yeah i actually do have a strain
that's perfect for what you're going to
do
so when it comes to this this is what i
should have started off in the beginning
and that's my scatter brain
i blame it on slash my adhd and some of
the cannabis i may smoke this
morning but
when it comes to cannabis every person
in the world every human being has an
endocannabinoid system
it's a system in your body that is meant
to
recep these cannabinoids so every person
in this world has a system believe it or
not every person says i can never smoke
weed it's so bad for you
oh
your body's meant to have it evolution
made us like a whole puzzle piece like
here if you just put this right here yes
perfectly yes
and the crazy thing about that is they
don't teach about it in college you'll
go to college for 10 years spend 100
grand or 200 grand as a pharmacy to be
like you know pharmacy
i don't know what you call them i'm
horrible at this stuff but to run a
pharmacy and be the head pharmacist guy
in order to do that you have to go to
college for a certain amount of years
and do this they don't teach you
anything about the endocannabinoid
system that blows my mind that blows my
mind how do you how do you spend all
that money and not learn that something
that's almost the biggest part of the
one of the biggest systems in your body
that's crazy i mean it
a good example of how our law system uh
kind of uh pushes against the truth of
science and it kind of like muddies the
waters of science and it's kind of
messed up actually but yeah go on
uh so in that aspect too the government
when they did their research they would
grow this wheat they would grow this
[__] brown weed
excuse my life this
crappy weed yes nickel frits and they
would they would grind it up with the
dirt that they grew it in and then they
would test that and that's how they
would do their research on cannabis and
that was back in the day but could you
believe that and that's the research
we've had through the government
now you you can correct me and there
will be podcasters and listeners i'm
sure they'll be like well
go ahead and do your research you'll
find out but uh i'm horrible with
yeah i'm horrible with explaining these
certain things i'm good at some things
but when it comes down to it the
government did a horrible job of doing
research on cannabis they turned it into
a schedule one drug and made it
impossible for people to really benefit
from it up until recently which is great
um so back to that part the
endocannabinoid system everybody has it
everybody has these cannabinoid
receptors um you just if your listener
look it up if you don't know it it's
awesome it'll
spark the light in your brain
what i do know about these receptors is
certain cannabinoids affect these
receptors
thc and cbd
thc is the psychoactive cannabis
compound or cannabinoid
cbd is the non-psychoactive cannabinoid
cannabidiol and then thc is
tetrahydrocannabinol
um they're awesome things they're the
they're the main compounds you find in
all cannabis plants and matter and most
of all
the most beneficial one is both of them
together believe it or not um
one without the other is great and can
work for you in certain ways but they
work better together
these things affect your endocannabinoid
system in most of the time a very
positive way depending on who you are
and how these certain strains affect you
um
so that's kind of like
the uh the knowledge you should know
when you look up cannabis
endocannabinoid system and then from
there it'll spark you these other things
it'll spark thc cbd and then the further
you get to it you'll get to the terpenes
and terpenoids that's the [__] that is
what we're going for if that makes sense
that's the therapeutic go ahead go ahead
oh no no no no so i just wanted to i
definitely want to get to terps and
terpenes um i want to elaborate on that
um but just so
so just finishing up with the
endocannabinoid system
um i remember watching a youtube video
actually it was like i mean it was
probably 10 minutes long wasn't very
long and it completely blew my mind when
i first learned about it and then i
think i started watching ted talks or
something about it started watching
people talk about it and it's so
interesting that that it's not
a more known thing it's one of our main
systems and it's just like oh well it's
it's illegal though so we pretend that
it's not actually there what like we
have so many different things that could
be helped and solved in so many like
ailments that could be cured um or you
know
alleviated rather so um when it comes to
what so what is the while we're right
here what's the difference between cbd
and thc like obviously thc is
psychoactive it gets you high cbd if you
just take cbd alone it has zero thc it
does not get you high you feel totally
fine
what are the effects that you
have you had just cbd by itself and have
you noticed like much of a calming
effect it's very subtle it's yes it's
very subtle um well so and that's it's
like a hard thin line of the
non-psychoactive i feel like for cbd um
thc so tc's definitely psychoactive
it's the one that you tend to it changes
your mind it alleviates certain things
and it does things that you feel
cbd
is the thin line where you they say it's
non-psychoactive you don't feel it but
if you do cbd the right way
and you do the right amount
you'll feel it in ways that you don't
understand are feeling like um
you you feeling anxiety you know i can
feel when i'm having anxiety and i can
feel when it goes away yeah yep so
that's you know when cbd they say it's
not psychoactive you don't feel it i
feel like i can feel it um but
not in a sense it's going to deter me or
you know um i guess what's that called
like mess with your mind kind of
psychoactively affect you um it's it's a
body feel relaxed feel a calm feel um
you know and you get that with certain
herbal medicines that you can take too
and certain aromas and smells essential
oils you don't you know there's there's
other things that are natural like cbd
that help you with this but uh cbd you
know and you don't feel them because you
don't get high
um so cbd is like the uh cbd is great
for it does a lot of the same things as
thc but
it it does them in a silent and clear
way a focused way it's a very clear feel
you know it's not a foggy which you will
get from thc or um not all thc but if if
that makes sense you know
it's not so much mental as it is like a
feeling of it's not utter relaxation
where it's like you just like you know
smoke some heavy drug or something
you're like oh whatever it's not it's it
it really is very subtle i would with me
when i was taking cbd fairly often i
would often notice of course the
benefits of not feeling inflammation
like i get neural inflammation which yes
depression and anxiety and stuff too but
outside of just the the inflammation and
all the benefits that that we get from
the alleviation of that with cbd um i i
feel i would notice kind of at the end
of the day like oh yeah like i didn't
really i wasn't overly worried about
stuff today wasn't exactly it's not that
you are suddenly you know you take it
and you're just waiting or you you take
your little tinker you take your gummy
and you're just like i am do i feel
anything it's it's not like that it's uh
you hit it on the nose you hit it on the
nail man that's that's to the t that's
it and like you know with certain
medicines and certain things it doesn't
happen right away you don't lose 100
pounds in a week
you know i mean maybe unless you shave
it off or something you know what i mean
you don't take certain medicines or
certain um you know herbal remedies and
they just i instantly take it away um
with cbd it's one of those things over
time and the the more you use it the
more it gets into your body the more
your body starts feeling it and really
using it to its power
and that's kind of like you know that's
where it comes in you don't it's not an
instant feel it's after time you're like
oh today was a lot less worrisome today
was oh man i didn't overthink today i
didn't overthink about driving down the
road you know
a couple days of that clarity for
someone who was stuck in their head who
they're caught in their loops they're
repeating their mean self-talk they've
got anxiety they've got depression like
i dealt with all these things like being
able to step outside of it for a few
days
i mean it's it's enough to kind of get
you get your head above water so yeah
like cbd
it's great and so i actually also had
the same similar effects with with thc
um i was able to stay home for a lot of
it um
like i like i wouldn't obviously
recommend someone just smoking weed and
going to their regular job every day if
that's if it doesn't fit their the mold
of their job
but
just being able to hang out with myself
just being able to like i got high and i
would go down and i would create i would
dj i would write some stuff i would read
i would stretch i would just hang out
with myself listen to music dance around
like a goofball
and i wouldn't have done that if i
wasn't like smoking and
it opens up i feel like it's not just
trying to get to that one thing okay i
smoke it and i have this many hours of
feeling good it's the build up of
effects of feeling good for a few days a
few weeks a few months like smoking
smoking weed or cbd whatever whatever it
is that someone's into it can give you
like a few days of alleviation to work
just enough to start kind of taking some
steps out of your depression or whatever
yeah yeah
that's that's exactly it man it's and
that's that's that's what makes it so
amazing i mean it's a natural thing it's
crazy to think this natural thing has
been outlawed and
banned and
took away from just everybody because
you know they didn't like how much money
that it was i don't even know the real
reason i think it was uh
you know
people like say it was the war on drugs
which was like a race thing too which it
makes sense it all does and that's what
sucks so it sucks they took this away
from everybody and it benefits everybody
because of some crappy
bull crap with politics and all the [__]
that goes on with that yep yeah dude i
mean we've got people like do the the
rates for
not just inflammation but like we look
at all these numbers of just people who
are depressed people who are this people
who are that people are doing with this
and then we have this do we have things
that are coming up hey this helps that
this helps us think outside of what that
you know it helps us not identify so
much with our illness if that's what's
going on we have all these things and
obviously it's not a blanket covering
you know different things affect
different people different set and
setting is obviously important some
people weed is just not for them and
that's okay too um
but so so when it comes to like your
personal anxiety dev what do you find
like what's the how do you describe the
difference because sometimes it's so
hard someone who has anxiety and they've
had it for years we just get so used to
that and you don't notice
how normal we've made our like everyday
anxiety sometimes or every day like
depression
not that we're a fault for it but
sometimes it just becomes whatever it's
just been happening for so long that
when you finally do get that kind of
breath of fresh air of being able to not
be anxious for a couple hours you're
like holy crap man i was really into it
i was in my head yes
so what's it like for you what's it like
for you
uh for me so uh you know what's funny i
i i get you know this sense of like
it's it's weird sometimes i i want to
get
um not manic but like i want to feel
like sometimes i get so zombied out that
i just want to feel up and i want to
feel up and going and
so that's why i love that that sativa
but uh really what
the effect with anxiety for me um it's
like
i used to
wake up in the morning and think and
think and think and think and
and that
it would be thinking i it
just this overthinking would create more
anxiety it's uh
it's hard to explain man uh because i
became it's became
necessarily not just a regimen but um i
don't have it anymore but
the anxiety
that's hard to say i still get anxiety i
still definitely get anxiety it's not
the same not like the everyday it's
normal yes yes it's and it's the instant
relief that marijuana provides for it um
that kind of
eases it and helps me think a way of
getting away from it but it
trying to narrow it down um when it
comes to my anxiety
it's it's stressors it's stress the the
marijuana has lifted us stress it's
pulled the stress away the overthinking
and that stressful that it causes
um
man it's it's hard it's hard to explain
that i guess
because it's
it's difficult to explain what's going
on in here into actual words yeah a lot
of times it's not it's kind of outside
of words in a way isn't it you know it's
a yeah it's yes feeling that you're
trying to describe it's kind of it's
even you know beyond emotions in a sense
you feel different emotions but it's
this it's understanding it's this
knowing within of okay yeah i'm fine and
well and and
i hate to say that like i i don't want
to make people think or the listeners
think that weed uh is a good
um like
high or like a a numbing because it
definitely can it definitely can but
um it
over time it it makes you think a little
bit more in a sense sometimes certain
things you know kind of like a mushroom
you know shrooms or lsd in those ways
where it kind of resets your brain or it
makes you think a little bit outside the
box i feel like with weed
it calms me to the point where i'm like
i don't need to stress so much about
that i've got two hours
i've got time
you know i've got why am i stressing
about this when i'm already dressed
ready to go
it's not here yeah i'm good i'm ready
it's still happening i'm gonna make it
on time why worry it's right now yeah
did you i lost you huh yeah i mean my
service should have been continuous i'm
hard lined in over here yeah i'm not
hard-lighted so it definitely was me
oh yeah weird it's fine i'll just uh
i'll edit it in post it'll be i'm sorry
about that bro hey sorry listeners it's
my internet missouri it's all good trust
me it'll sound we were exploring the
differences between indica and sativa so
someone who doesn't know anything about
weeds but they've maybe heard of indica
and sativa what do we got what's our
differences okay so that's where it came
into when i was talking about anxiety
and you know the certain weeds that
affect me and differentiate for me and
whatever
so when it comes to indica sativa now uh
the truth behind flower right now is
it's hard to really pinpoint exactly
what flower is or what strain that is
but growers think they know for the most
part and most of these guys have kind of
dialed it in
um but when it comes to flower i feel
like most of strains are going to be a
hybrid they're going to be a hybrid as
in they're going to be leaning this way
or this way and
people like to say what i like to say is
into couch you are relaxed you are
[Music]
calm you are feeling
you are feeling it
well um and that's a body feel very
heavy body feel usually
very easy on the mind
and usually it's like a night time
people like to say or
just
for usual good pain relief
anxiety too
a lot of those things even sometimes
people that have eating disorders and
need to eat more uh smoke something and
you'll get hungry
um sativa sativa is usually known or
what people like to refer to as like a
daytime and upper if you're uh you know
in some places um uh it's energy it's
uplifting it's awakening um it heightens
your senses it's a cerebral high a head
change
um i like to do what i would like to do
back in the day when i was at a rec
state i'd be like hey what strains going
to make this movie pop out to me um
what what strain is going to make this
hype just super bright and exciting
and that's that was that's the sativas i
like you know those ones that are head
changing just it makes everything so
much vibrant
um it's cool the weed does that to you
too um but that's the sativa versus
indica like uh uppity daytime energy
uplifting um
sometimes the bad or cons of sativas
anxiety paranoia
um
uh
you know overthinking that it can create
that anxiety that you're trying to get
away from
um so would you would you suggest like
as just kind of a broad brush stroke
it's people who don't smoke much they
like they want to try it out would you
suggest starting with an indica first or
a hybrid
i would suggest um you know in a lot of
these stores a lot of these growers have
got it dialed into where um and
especially with experience
personally when it comes to asking for
these certain things always ask your
budtender what they think
their opinion what they would go for
now
sometimes you get the ones that try to
upsell you find something but most of
the time both tenders are really good
and they'll give you that uh you know i
like this and you know the personal
experience is what i prefer
but when it comes to uh new beginner
smoking i liked the
or
in
arts right now we've been want to smoke
we get beginners that want to eat or
even vape or um you know uh topicals
um so i i would definitely start if
you're gonna smoke a hybrid a good
hybrid or indica leaning so you don't
get two in your head and that's where
people get that paranoia with sativas
they might have smoked for the first
time and it might have been a very good
sativa and it got them racy and their
mind going and they're like nope never
doing this again and that's
that really sucks i don't know how many
people have encountered that have
experienced that and
um you know it's the ones that give it
another chance and have the right
knowledge or somebody that's giving them
the right knowledge that can dwindle
make that a little bit better and easier
yeah and also not like smoking a whole
joint or your first time or like if
you're
a homie who smokes and you have someone
else trying it out or you you're giving
someone some weed who doesn't smoke very
often or really ever like dude just tell
them to take a tiny little hit it's all
they need
and if in 20 minutes if they don't feel
like that much maybe take another one
whatever but don't you don't have to
strap to the moon man
no
yeah don't go give somebody a beginner a
[__] dab and make them hallucinate
and not know who they are
i mean i've
go yeah i've experienced some crazy
stuff you know i mean i've dabbed a lot
but i still get those first time giant
dabs that like wreck oh
yeah well we want people to enjoy that
week we don't want them to go and try it
and not not like it uh you know i don't
want my friend to
um smoke something and never want to
smoke it again because it just it didn't
hit him right you know
um just you know hopefully those
listeners are nice to their friends you
know i have some friends that i might
give something but they've experienced
it they'll be fine no
yeah they're veterans at this point yeah
that's the thing is you want to
yeah you don't really need to go you
know you don't really need to go full
bore and it's and it really can be
honestly like a scott like almost a
traumatizing thing for people if you do
just smoke a crazy ton out the gate like
it's
it and also set and setting that's a big
thing with uh with like psilocybin or
lsd or even mdma a lot of this research
they're doing
at maps the multi
multi-disciplinary association for
psychedelic studies um that's a huge
thing that i always hear in all the
interviews and podcasts and stuff that i
listen from them is set and setting like
you make sure you know where you're at
make sure you know like
okay i don't have to drive in 30 minutes
you know if this is your first time
smoking or if this is like you don't
really smoke you just want to really
enjoy it get into a safe spot you know
have some pla have some like some time
like okay i don't have to do anything
for six hours i don't have to do
anything until tomorrow whatever it is
you want to just kind of set yourself up
oh i i paid those bills i i went through
and i paid my phone bill really quick
cool set to the side that's done cool i
got this thing i got the food that i
might want later already or i got yes
ready to rock and roll you know whatever
it is set your set your environment up
and then set your like internal uh life
organizational environment up as well
you know yes yes most definitely i mean
that's the main thing you don't want to
go like you know
my thing is
don't bring your guy that you're trying
to smoke with her first time in the car
like i actually i don't smoke in my car
too often at all because it's just scary
to me but uh you know like don't make it
a scary setting where you have to hide
it you know be able to do in a setting
where you're just comfortable exactly
just come from comfortability high or
not high that's the most important thing
um when you're you're trying this out
uh
and also you know
hopefully the good advice from somebody
or try to do some research on yourself
before uh jumping into it because you
don't want to ruin it for yourself
yeah right exactly exactly um okay so
just rounding out on indica in sativa
basically we're kind of at a point right
now where everything's everything's kind
of hybridy it's a little bit hard to
tell right so it's uh
but but still would you basically kind
of say a little more indica leaning if
you want that more body yeah a little
more sativa for that head high euphoria
yes yes true true and you will find some
strains you know a big thing too when it
comes to cannabis everybody's
biologically different
everybody
i've had people come into the store and
the sativa affects them the complete
opposite it gives them that indica body
high
it makes them just relax and you know
and then i get those people that come in
and they they smoke indica and it gets
them racy it gets them it gives them
anxiety and i'm like dude you're that
that small percentage let's see what we
can do for you and i usually try to put
them towards a hybrid leaning towards
one way or another and then we know how
well that's going to work and then we
can move towards like
a closer to the sativa you know what and
when i like to get back to that that's
hybrids
there's hybrids that are depending on
experience that are like uh they lean a
little to the sativa so they're a little
uplifting but not too much or the ones
that are a little more relaxing but you
can still do your day-to-day activities
you know um that's what i i like to lean
towards a hybrid leading because it's
never too much of the other you know and
that's that's personally what i like
i've always i used to smoke hybrids
non-stop
now i like to mix it up and dab a little
bit because i like to sometimes i like
those racy feels when it comes to flour
certain sativas you know it's it's a
little fun dude i'm totally with you uh
joe rogan actually talks about uh
sometimes like he'll get super stoned
and he loves having that almost like
anxiety because you're cause you're
stuck with it and like after a while
like it actually kind of creates a
little bit of courage in in a strange
way because after a while like once you
get kind of used to smoking a few days
in a row or whatever you're like okay i
have this anxiety feeling but what am i
gonna do i gotta write it out so like
what's up like it's almost like practice
against your anxious thoughts and then
you know 20 minutes later you get out of
it and you're like oh i had nothing to
be anxious about but that was kind of
cool that i [__] stood i was like i
could handle it i'm good oh come on
anxiety you know exactly exactly man
i personally like when i have people
come in they're like man that [__] made
me feel weird i'm like yes cool let me
know i want it um also
um
to get a little bit further after that
indica sativa
terpenes and terpenoids if you don't
mind me going into a little i'd love to
carry on um terpenes are awesome
actually i'm gonna grab something while
we're here um terpenes are awesome
they're a compound found in almost
everything that's like a plant-wise
it's a an aroma it's a therapeutic
compound can you still hear me well i
can okay
terpenes are just
they're what make the weeds smell
the way they smell and there's science
that proves that these certain
terpenoid compounds uh make you feel the
way you feel from certain strains and
weeds
when it comes to that like i i need them
in front of me because i'm still like
it's still learning you're still
learning my favorite terpene is
beta-carothylene um it's one of the only
terpenes that if it's the only terpene
that affects what your cannabinoid
receptors
which is cool so it's the only thing
that in a sense kind of affects with you
you know
uh it it [__] with you for sure
um so like a mere scene mircine is also
found in hops
that's one of the most common terpenes
found in flower
mircine is here it is um
it
[Music]
it's found in indicas a lot it's a
sedating terpene it's a relaxing terpene
it smells of hops it smells of mangoes
it's got like a sweet kind of smell to
it a musky sweet smell
my favorite terpene beta-carotelline
it's a peppery spicy um
like cinnamon smell black pepper smell
um you know gorilla glue you know
strange blue
you get that kind of
musky almost spicy herbal peppery smell
in most good gorilla glue grown good
gorilla glue that's that beta-carotene
terpene
um now let's see with master yoda
try to think of your strain yoda i
believe it's a sativa leaning it's not a
full sativa it's a hybrid sativa i'm
pretty sure
um it i believe it has some limonene in
there and limonene
is an uplifting terpene um it's a
citrusy smell um not all you know not
super citrusy but just like a hint you
know um it's uh
lemony see and okay so limiting is also
believe it or not it's an antibacterial
and anti-fungal terpene so
it's it's beneficial in other ways than
just you know you would think in
alleviating you know your mind or your
body
that's what's cool about terpenes
there's so many more and i hope the
listeners look up terpenes and it helps
guide them towards what they want to
find in flower
that's currently what we do with the
store i work at we list all the common
terpenes some information about them
what they help with
anti-inflammatory anti-cancer
pain relief
some are
like they get rid of the appetite i
don't know the exact words for that um
some of them are great for depression
anxiety you know
terpenes also are you know that's the
smell that's that smell you get in that
flower so you're already getting
terpenes when you smell it that's cool
[__] you know
terpenes affect you through that way um
and then there's science that proves
that it affects you smoking in in in
taking it smoking ways
um i i don't know the whole science
behind eating terpenes
um i think it's more of the smell that
affects you and your you know your
senses
right
but terpenes are two prints awesome
that's that's the coolest [__] that's
when people say i want the terps they
want those dabs or that flower that's
tasty that's stanky that that's just
ripe you know um personally i love weed
that smells like you just stepped in a
big pile of dog poop
i love that weed that is my favorite
yes yes
one more terpene that's a big one that
you'll find on uh common have you ever
tried like
sour tangy
or uh you know citrusy strains some
strains that taste very orangey
yeah yeah me uh
and i used to smoke a ton of like when
it came to citrus that's that's what we
would smoke when we'd make music all the
time okay so that is going to be
valencia valencine is found in oranges
and tamarinds and and citruses um and
that is like the most one of the most
tastiest terpenes um one of my favorites
to be honest too
there's another one uh terpenoline
terpenoline is uh when you get just
straight terpenoline in a bottle and you
smell it it smells like some really good
um recreational drugs uh think of
diesel uh listeners um awesome stuff but
that's what's cool is this is all found
in flour in in bud marijuana
and it's it's so cool and fascinating
and when you open this up in your brain
and you get into it you find out certain
terpenes that work better for you and
and certain why certain strains affect
you these ways better than others and
that's the coming to an understanding of
flour
and how it works for you or what it does
for you and and that's that's what i'm
trying to get at when it comes to
patients i want to find something that
works
and and you know why it works you know
right right dude in like having i mean
where we're like guinea pigs in the
coolest way though too you know
especially the legal recreational states
because as time progresses you know over
the next 30 years we take all this you
know new data of okay okay so this
terpene affects anti-inflammatory the
anti-inflammatory response this terpene
affects people with depression okay and
we have all this data which may maybe
kind of anecdote in a lot of ways but
then it'll start to build on actual like
intellectual i mean like you guys are
just going to keep getting smarter and
smarter behind the counter educating the
people who go in because like you do
think about when you go in to buy some
booze or something i'm sure i'm sure if
you go to the right liquor store a lot
of these people probably do know a good
amount oh hey that was distilled in this
place and that's from you know germany
or this is you know that sort of thing
but when it comes to
you know kind of this there is this
innate medicinal enjoyable happiness joy
part of of buying weed and as we get
more information the the tenders and the
people who are like supplying us with
with the weed and the knowledge of it
are gonna be able to know more and more
yeah yeah so it's just really cool where
we're at as a society you know as as we
get farther and farther along this path
it's gonna start opening up different
sides of this that we didn't even really
think about before like all of the
different things we can now help and
individualize and hey based off of a
study of you know 6 000 people in
washington 25 000 people in oregon this
many people in california they smoked
this strain and it helped them with this
yeah it's
great man
it's so exciting it's so exciting so
where do you where do you see
where where do you see like the future
of
we're here in 2021 towards the end
but do you do you see would you say
within the next let's say 10 years maybe
even 15. you think it'll be federally
legal
national oh man that would be a thing
it's funny you bring that up because i
always i still talk to my friends like
all my close friends and just anybody i
would get in this conversation with but
i've uh i used to say like within five
years about
five years ago
that it was going to be fairly legal
i thought a lot of politics would make
it happen but i'm surprised it hasn't
but i believe um
i believe in in 10 years or less from
this year
we will be completely federally legal i
really believe so
i think
every state is becoming more medically
legal um and then from there it's just
recreational and
all the states surrounding these states
you know um are are opening up and
becoming more apt to it um i mean i
think idaho and a couple other states
might be the last ones ever go fully
wreck but
you could find cbd in just about every
state that's a start that happened quick
too i feel yeah
um the unfortunate thing of cbd is
everybody tried to get on it and
inflated and uh
um i know i don't hate on cbd too much
but i hate on uh cbd companies that are
you know ripping people off at the cbd
amounts that they're selling when it
comes to cbd you need a good amount um
you know most most everybody you 10
milligrams a day i don't think we'll do
you too much uh yeah just cbd cbd's just
you got to be careful cbd you know don't
buy from the internet um if you do
make sure to do your research on that
company you're buying from you know
that's the biggest thing that's why you
can't buy thc online um it goes through
rigorous amounts of testing and and uh
you know certain uh
certain tests that make it
that you need you need in order to be
able to smoke it you know um
you know tests on microbials and
bacteria and
minerals um you don't want that stuff in
your wheat you don't want it so that's
why you got to be careful where you buy
it and who you're buying it from yeah if
you've got some dude in their backyard
pretty much like converting their old
moonshine making station to a cbd making
station you know you're going to end up
with some heavy metals
[__] you don't want and it's going to be
inconsistent i do
i do cbd md that it is online um but
they i think they have like a ton of
third-party tested they're very rigorous
with their testing um
i've read all of their stuff and it
convinced me enough and i i was taking a
pretty high amount of cbd from them for
a while yeah that's as long as you do
you're testing your research on it you
know that's my biggest thing gas station
cbds
right you know yeah because i i think a
lot of people you know because it's if
it's maybe i'll try cbd and then you're
going to you know get a pack of gum or
pay for your gas and you're like oh all
right let's try that if that's your
experience with with cbd you might not
have really experienced like the the
benefits that you could be experiencing
just like we were talking about if your
first experience with wheat is like
smoking an entire like really heavy
sativa you might be sent to the moon and
have a bad time you also don't want to
be buying that gas station cbd and
saying that's what represents yeah just
like the calming anti-inflammatory
effects of cbd connecting to our no camp
can you please system definitely be
careful don't buy those cartridges from
the the gas station because uh you know
that's what was on the news a while back
with people passing away from you know
these certain vapes
yeah that's the gas station stuff be
careful you know as much as you want to
be careful with jewels and nicotines
everybody to each their own just be
careful
i love you all just be careful
i feel that i feel that um all right man
what do you what do you got going on in
your world like what's your w
what's your continuation on this journey
like you're just going to keep learning
keep taking off oh man keep teaching
people
yeah my goal michael obviously to stay
in this industry for as long as i can i
would love to be like a
uh
you know consultant and helping and help
a consultant many ways whether it be
helping a company or a store start up or
helping patients find the right medicine
or certain recreational people find
their right medicine and stuff but uh my
goal is to obviously just gain as much
knowledge as i can
um
uh i would like to try and be in other
states i want to see how these other
states do it and that's kind of why i
went to missouri you know i seen how
washington does it i got to see how
oregon does it um now i'm seeing how
missouri does it and then from here on
it's the next state you know uh new
jersey's opening up new york's becoming
legal new mexico there's it's just it's
not going away um so i plan to stay in
it and you know maybe we'll have a
podcast another you know however long
from now and see where i'm at and what
state i'm in next you know i would love
to we're going to have a five-year
reunion for the next year
whatever year devon and cannabis where
is he now
there's like some scientists in a lab in
louisiana
oh man oh yeah i'm researching how cbd
affects your placebo you know
yeah something super complex yes
i love that i'm uh
i don't know i'm hoping i've been kind
of asking a lot of people around here in
texas um
what they think what their opinions are
if they think that they see it becoming
legal um you know the next five years or
whatever a lot of people seem to think
that austin austin in particular will
find a way to legalize the recreational
use and then from there we'll see what
happens to the rest of texas but austin
itself is really this blue chunk in in
in a red state you know i see
i see that i hope man um i really hope
so because i know right now in texas
it's like a
a felony if you have a gram of
concentrates that's ridiculous
yeah yeah it's still so rigorous it's
still pretty tough i want to say that
the um the delta eight
what is still technically legal it's in
this very foggy in between it might like
by the time this conversation comes out
it might not even be whatever but uh it
was legal and you could still order it
like online or whatever
dell date which is
delta a is uh derived from the cbd plan
and hemp not from the thc eight so
so it's thc nine is
the molecule that is in regular like
weed that you buy that has the euphoria
in the psychosomatic symptoms uh but thc
a is the molecule derived from
cbd and it is a little bit different of
a high all right yeah delta eight uh
delta eight is definitely uh i feel like
it's more of a feel you know what they
do is they they basically take this cbd
or hemp uh derived cbd and they alter it
and they alter it to give this other
effect um i'd say be very careful with
uh delta eight any any listeners that
are trying it out um i've i've tried it
personally myself and i didn't feel it
too much and i think it's because i'm an
avid user and um you know i know certain
things to feel for maybe but i've had
some people take it and it it affected
them in a in a bad way um it was
interesting more than they expected you
know and that's that's the scary part um
and it's because it's so new there's not
a whole lot of nobody knows much about
it and um you know we know where it
comes from and we know what it where it
comes from and what it does but when you
alter something it's going to be create
a different effect you know yeah it
starts getting a little iffy there i
know i got mine from i got i had gotten
mine a while back from 3g delta it's
been a while now but
three chi or three g something like that
i don't know
i looked through i was on reddit for a
long time researching and it seemed like
it was something trusting i mean don't
take my report please do your own
research whatever but it seemed like it
was good and i did enjoy um
it was really cool to smoke it and
really just kind of contemplate how does
this feel differently than than a
regular thc high and how does it affect
me and and how does it how long does it
last like like it's just just just like
with any strain where it's very fun to
me to explore like what does the strain
make me do oh does this strain make me
want to go outside more does it make me
want to do this does it describe my
anxiety it's kind of the same thing but
yeah so delta a is it's pretty much weed
but there's less
less traceable amounts of thc in it so
some people would recommend it for
states that are legal yeah and it's cool
it's cool they're coming out these
things and these certain um you know
other compounds of cbd or cannabis
because it's a legal thing you know it
makes it easier access and it almost you
know helps people kind of get into this
this other alternative medicine you know
cannabis period and once they open their
mind to that you know the door is open
let's let's see what else is out there
and let's go check out a store and see
what they can tell us you know let's
let's let's move on from the gas station
and see what somebody that you know
sells us for a living can tell us and
that's that's cool to me that's that's
the positive side of delta and cbd and
gas stations you know it's it's more
normalized it's it's it's another touch
in people's faces and their eyes you
know no doubt no doubt well okay so last
thing i would like to do is just do or
wait and i have two more two more quick
things last thing before the last thing
would be uh someone who's never smoked
weed or maybe they've never purchased
wheat in a recreational state even
it might be intimidating to walk into a
store you don't know what you do you
don't know how you don't know what
you're talking about you don't want to
sound like a knucklehead it's kind of
the same intimidation we get going to
like a new gym a lot of the times it's
kind of intimidating like i don't really
know how to work out i'll do i that's a
picture of someone doing that so i guess
i'll follow what they're doing but when
it comes to walking into a recreational
state and you want to try something
what what's the best experience like
like take us through this we walk in the
door what happens what are we looking
for
so you're going to walk in and i'm going
to ask you you know hey what are you
here for and you're going to usually
tell me you know if it's a
if it's like a recreational activity you
know or if you're going to tell me it's
a certain thing that you're trying to
achieve or feel and i'm instantly going
to be like well i've got plenty of ways
to make this happen for you um you know
in in in recreational or medical
i'm going to show you these uh these
flowers and these products obviously but
i'm gonna i'm gonna ask you too you know
what do you like what do you what do you
want to experience do you want to taste
do you want to feel
um do you want to see you know what what
are you looking to achieve and there's
so many things people are coming in for
um and then i i you know i ask you
you know what what
i guess what what you're not trying to
achieve you know because i want to set
you up with the right thing so i want to
make sure and ask you you know
what do you want to stay away from you
know what do you what kind of feeling do
you not want to have um and then i also
ask you know what your your experience
is with this stuff um if you had none
then i asked you you know what brought
you in here
and usually it's it's a it's a relative
or it's a friend and i ask them you know
and and then it leads to the
conversation while they say you know
i've never tried it before well actually
i hit it one time with my friend that
told me to come in here and i i trust
them so i came in you know um
but even with those beginners that are
coming in um just ask questions tell the
butt tender you know this is what i do
want this is what i want to feel um
and if you don't know what to say just
you know ask them you know ask them hey
what what's
tell them what you're trying to achieve
that's the biggest thing you know when
it comes to just what are you trying to
get from this what are you trying to
benefit from this cannabis because we
have so many ways and and like you said
different products or different ways to
partake or to achieve these so what
works best for you do you want something
that you can drink i got those too you
know
there you go yeah yeah that's another
thing they might they might recommend
edibles too yes which is a whole another
side we can talk about in another
podcast but oh gosh
yeah because i actually don't have the
um i don't know if i don't have the
liver enzyme enzymes
but for whatever reason my system does
not process edible marijuana i can take
quite a bit and i feel absolutely
nothing you're one of those a little
that percentage you know there's that
price percentage of people biologically
different that get affected differently
but we get those people come in that you
know they'll eat a 100 milligrams 200
milligrams 300 milligrams edibles and
not feel a thing but then they'll smoke
a bowl and feel it right yeah so some
people will take five to ten milligrams
and they're drooling on their couch
pillows you know like which is hell yeah
man that's awesome it's and that's
really it's just your liver doesn't have
that enzyme that breaks it into uh the
uh i know the exact i don't know the
exact word but yeah it's it's just an
enzyme that your body isn't creating or
doing and that's not a bad thing it's
not bad thing at all what would work for
you jake and what i would recommend when
it comes to an edible if you get a gummy
or a tincture put it underneath your
tongue
sublingual um that will affect you i
think you should be able to feel that
way um the liver you know breaks it down
and turns into these enzymes and does
these things but sublingually it gets
into your bloodstream that way and that
might that might help you might be able
to feel it that way a little bit i'm
gonna have to explore that just shoving
some some weed cookies yeah
when uh when the time comes and you're
ready to uh partake you just let me know
we'll do we'll do man i appreciate it um
yeah yeah that's awesome uh so dude yeah
listeners anybody who wants to go and
explore a weed store it's not
intimidating walk into the door i mean
you have you basically have them all in
a glass case you can see everything it's
usually bright in here it's it's a nice
environment it's welcoming the people
who work there like what they do that's
the biggest thing who doesn't want to go
to a place where everybody working there
likes what they do and like it really
comes across when you come in like dude
i would have times where i'd go in
anxious kind of depressed i'm like i'm
like pretty much wearing a hood hoodie
you know like i'm like i don't really
want to be here but i'm whatever and
just kind of describe what's going on
what you want and it's they'll explain
what's going on they'll help you out so
just walk in be open and just kind of
talk with the person behind behind the
counter and then go help you out i like
to think it was like planet fitness
there's no judges no judgment zone man
yeah you know come in here and feel free
to be yourself as much as you can
because we're ourselves we just want to
help you you know we just want to help
make your day better or brighter yes yes
100 all right dev um i appreciate you so
much thank you for your time this one
last question that i uh presented as the
question before the last question would
be
what does
the world need more of right now
[Music]
the world needs
more
love
just more love man
more love for everybody uh in and out
this or that uh you or you or him or her
or she or he or they are they
everybody just needs love more love in
this world man if we had more love we'd
have uh we'd have happier people i feel
like you know
love love for everybody man
yes i love it i love that very much man
that's that's the perfect answer that's
the
that's the what i'm secretly wanting to
hear
as the answer for the junkyard love
podcast yes very much we need more love
um
man i love that you came on here i love
that you offered me your time dev i
really appreciate that you
are you know willing and open to kind of
share what you know and just kind of
allow me to poke and pop product your
brain and see what comes out it's been
great to be a part of it man i never
thought uh you know
we'd be in a podcast you know 20 years
later coming from catlin
right man oh man
uh it's awesome i appreciate it brother
i really do
yeah it's it's beautiful how life goes
isn't it
yeah and we're you're in texas i'm in
missouri this is you know yeah who would
have thought like what like even if you
asked us five years ago like where are
you going to live in five years we
wouldn't say missouri or texas but he's
not at all man not at all we are
yeah bro it's been great man i really
appreciate it jake thanks for letting me
be a part of this man i hope uh
listeners liked it and they can get some
get some light bulbs blown off in their
head about cannabis and terpenes and you
know help them guide their experience
yeah i love it thank you for your
expertise man thank you for your wisdom
um we'll uh we'll definitely have to do
do a round two of this in the future so
we'll just we'll see how it pans out
sounds good brother i appreciate you
all right man you have a good rest your
day and listeners you have a good rest
of your day as well uh
take care of yourselves if you're gonna
dip into the weed world trust yourself
set setting just take a little bit
um listen to the person behind the
counter do some research it's this
wonderful cool world that can open up so
you know don't be afraid of it and if
you haven't drank any water today you're
a total piece of turd you got to drink
some water get some water in yeah at
least come on yes at least a bottle
right now leave this podcast right now
it's about to end right now go chug a
bottle water dev i appreciate you man
yes later jake
pour it down your throat that's what
you're going to say
now i'll just say put it half in your
ball and get some fresh water and then
throw the rest down your throat
that's so perfect yes all right man have
a good rest today bro later you two
later bro
at what age should we learn to have
better conversations with ourselves
[Music]
knowledge is power
reality is
[Music]